Matthew Zuckman

I'm a passionate design leader—transforming patterns, insights, and opportunities into compelling experiences. I shift design cultures and build empowered teams. I develop product and marketing systems that work across platforms, screens, and customers. And I've got the track record to prove it.

Employment History

Udemy Director of Design

2014-2016

Yahoo

Design Director, Communications

Mail, Calendar, Groups, Contacts, Notepad 2013-2014

Yahoo Design Director, Commerce

Autos, Travel, Shopping, Homes, Games 2010-2013

Publicis Modem VP/Director, User Experience

PayPal, LG, UBS, SunPower Foundation 2008-2010

Real Branding Director, User Experience

Disney, ABC, ESPN, Anheuser-Busch, Lipton, Red Lobster, USGA 2007-2008

- Established the discipline of design within the company by defining and implementing key principles and practices; evolved as the company grew from 50 employees to over 200.
- Instituted processes for the collaboration, review, and knowledge sharing across multiple organization levels that created an environment for transparency, mentorship, and growth.
- Established the patterns, frameworks, and elements for brand and product, creating guidelines to enable quality production at speed.
- Led the large scale, front-end redesign of Mail and Calendar for an audience of 300 million customers.
- Transformed the team's culture, tools, and the working models, increasing performance for the existing team while hiring and expanding the span of control for the group.
- Strengthened the cross-discipline team via models that inspired deep thinking, ideation, efficiency, and strategic alignment.
- Worked across the Yahoo network to define hiring practices, charters, and review criteria to ensure the quality of design.
- Led the development of lead-generation opportunities by focusing on meaningful values, increasing page views and time spent 30-50% across the portfolio.
- Built a multi-disciplinary team of eight teammates within four months; expanded portfolio to take on additional business lines.
- Drove the re-imagining of commerce portfolio by producing a forward-looking vision that informed the organization's strategy.
- Oversaw the re-launches of PayPal's consumer and business sites, bringing double-digit growth in lead generation and adoption.
- Supported LG Mobile's digital strategy by delivering rich-presence marketing experiences for all new phone releases.
- Recruited and managed team of designers; directed utilization and billable percentages across teams and accounts.
- Led the joint SOAPnet/agency team through all phases of large redesign project: developing community, architecture, and content strategies for all screens.
- Grew the experience design practice by providing thought leadership, mentoring designers, and pitching new business.
- Worked with company leadership to develop processes and deliverables, defining the scoping models for client engagement.

Earlier positions

AKQA

Microsoft Xbox, Target, Nike, Autodesk, McDonald's, 2008, 2010

Masters Program Study Advisor, Academy of Art University

2008-2010

Senior User Experience Designer, McCann Worldgroup

Microsoft, 2007

Senior User Experience Designer, Eleven Inc.

The Doctors Company, 2006-2007

Senior Information Architect, Tribal DDB

Clorox, Armor All, Hidden Valley, Fresh Step, NBC Universal, 2005-2006

Senior User Experience Designer, EVB

AT&T, Wrigley, Adidas, Leapfrog, 2005-2007

Lead Interaction Designer, Enterpulse

Albertsons, 2004

Information Architect, Grey Global Group

Oracle, Wells Fargo, 2003-2004

Executive Producer, Epylon Corporation

1999-2001

Producer, Foote, Cone & Belding

3Com, Sega Dreamcast, 1998 - 1999

Producer, Think New Ideas

Silicon Graphics, 1997 - 1998

Designer, Printz Electronic Design

Asante, 1995 - 1996

Education

Rhode Island School of Design, Providence, RI

BFA, industrial design, with emphasis on human/machine interface design

University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN

Liberal arts, with emphasis on economic and political sciences